# **BENJAMIN FOLKS**

E: <u>bfolks2@gmail.com</u> • M: (630)-217-5872 1143 W Wrightwood Ave #1F, Chicago, IL 60614

bfolks2.pythonanywhere.com, www.benfolks.com, https://github.com/bfolks2

#### AEROSPACE-SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Multi-faceted engineer with experience working on project teams in numerous fast-paced environments. Aims to combine Aerospace Engineering Degree, software development experience gained in professional environments, and real-world aviation experience as an *FAA Certified Instrument-Rated Pilot*.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python/Django

SolidWorks 3D CAD

JavaScript/Ember.js

VB.NET/VBA

• Esprit CAD/CAM

HTML/CSS

- Direct knowledge and understanding of flight instruments onboard general aviation aircraft
  - 6-pack Primary Instrument Display, Aspen glass panel Primary Flight Display
  - Navigation systems equipped with Dual VOR's, CDI, DME, and GPS (Garmin GTN 650)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### RedShelf • Chicago, IL • January 2018 - Present

Web development company providing digital content for educational institutions

#### **Full-Stack Software Engineer**

- Work within an Agile software development team to address product-driven enhancements and JIRA tickets, while simultaneously building out new business-driven applications using SCRUM methodology
- Manage Django/Python backend data services for use with internal and external integrations
- Optimize Python tasks to be run daily that synchronize the internal database with external sources
- Construct unit, integration, and acceptance (Selenium) tests with Python in order to complete an initiative to increase coverage across the code-base to over 90%
- Build backend REST API to handle CRUD methods, as well as other custom operations, utilized by an entirely new, internal frontend Ember.js application
- Create endpoints which authenticate external clients and grant them access to serialized representations of internal data models, based on user permissions

#### AdThrill • Chicago, IL • December 2017 - Present, (Part-Time)

Start-up website for users to watch and rate advertisements (adthrill-prod.herokuapp.com)

# **Lead Python Backend Engineer**

- Construct backend Python/Django model definitions to maintain and analyze all relevant user data
- Create search algorithms to optimize matches between businesses and their target user audiences
- Deployed the first live production version of the site, supported by continuous enhancement releases

# DP Technology - ESPRIT • Rosemont, IL • July 2012 - December 2017

Developer and supplier of computer-aided manufacturing (CAM) software for CNC machine tools

# Senior Manufacturing/Software Engineer

- Create technical designs and generate manufacturing processes for concurrent OEM projects
- Build SolidWorks CAD assemblies of dynamic machine models utilized for digital part verification
- Determine processes and tooling necessary for manufacturing aerospace and automotive turn-key parts, in order to produce time studies and fully functional milling/turning programs
- Plan and create VB.NET/VBA applications within the ESPRIT API to increase automation of tool selection and machining processes for a range of CNC mills, lathes, and multitasking machine tools
- Travel onsite to aerospace and US government clients to oversee technical projects, including NASA Glenn, Woodward Inc, Northstar Aerospace, Tinker AFB

#### **EDUCATION**